"irb_number","study_title","pi_name","research_type","nct_num","enrolling"
"HSC 08-5085","A Clinical Evaluation of the Medtronic Endeavor® Resolute Zotarolimus-Eluting Coronary Stent System in the Treatment of De Novo Lesions in Native Coronary Arteries with a Reference Vessel Diameter of 2.25 mm to 4.2 mm.","Paul Teirstein","Cardiology and Vascular Diseases","NCT#","Yes"
"HSC-00-111","(NSABP B-31) A Randomized Trial Comparing the Safety and Efficacy of Adriamycin and Cyclophosphamide Followed by Taxol (AC --> T) to that of Adriamycin and Cyclophosphamide Followed by Taxol Plus Herceptin (AC --> T + H) in Node Positive Breast Cancer Patients who have Tumors that Overexpress HER2","James Mason","Obstetrics and Gynecology","NCT00004067","No"
"HSC-00-112","NSABP C-07: A Clinical Trial Comparing 5-Fluorouracil (5-FU) Plus Leucovorin (LV) and Oxaliplatin with 5-FU Plus LV for the Treatment of Patients With Stages II and III Carcinoma of the Colon","William Miller","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00004931","No"
"HSC-03-2329","Allogeneic Hematopoietic Progenitor Cell Transplantation from Unrelated Donors","Jeffrey Andrey","Hematology and Oncology","NOT LISTED","Yes"
"HSC-03-2338","Research Database for Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation and Marrow Toxic Injuries","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01166009","Yes"
"HSC-03-2339","Research Sample Repository for Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00495300","Yes"
"HSC-04-2544","A Trial of Tandem Autologous Stem Cell Transplants + / - Post Second Autologous Transplant Maintenance Therapy versus Single Autologous Stem Cell Transplant Followed by Matched Sibling Nonmyeloablative Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplant for Patients with Multiple Myeloma (BMT-CTN Protocol 0102)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00075829","No"
"HSC-05-2825","Filgrastim-Mobilized Peripheral Blood Stem Cells for Allogeneic Transplantation with Unrelated Donors (An NMDP Protocol)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00511550","Yes"
"HSC-07-4835","Genetic Investigation of Solid Tumors (GIST) Cohort","James Mason","Obstetrics and Gynecology","NCT01005225","Yes"
"HSC-08-5019","The PARTNER Trial: Placement of AoRTic TraNscathetER Valves Trial with COHORT B as CONTINUED ACCESS [Edwards Study # 2006-06-US]","Paul Teirstein","Cardiology and Vascular Diseases","NCT#00530894","Yes"
"HSC-99-1437","Project Title:SWOG 9438:Total Body Irradiation, Etoposide, Cyclophosphamide, and Autologous Peripheral Blood Stem Cell Transplantation Followed by Randomization to Therapy with Interleukin-2 Vs. Observation for Patients with Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma, A BMT Study, Phase III","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00002649","No"
"HSC-99-1466","A Three-Arm Randomized Trial to Compare Adjuvant Adriamycin and Cyclophosphamide Followed by Taxotere (AC-T); Adriamycin and Taxotere (AT); and Adriamycin. Taxotere, and Cyclophosphamide (ATC) in Breast Cancer Patients with Positive Axillary Lymph Nodes (NSABP Protocol B-30)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00003782","No"
"HSC-99-1594","SWOG 9581: Phase III Randomized Study of Adjuvant Immunotherapy with Monoclonal Antibody 17-1A Versus No Adjuvant Therapy Following Resection for Stage II (Modified Astler-Coller B2) Adenocarcinoma of the Colon","William Miller","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00002968","No"
"IRB-09-5125","A Double-Blind, Randomized Phase II Study Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Sorafenib Compared to Placebo in Ovarian Epithelial Cancer or Primary Peritoneal Cancer Patients who have achieved a Complete Clinical Response after Standard Platinum/Taxane Containing Chemotherapy (Bayer 12007)","Bridgette Duggan","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00791778","No"
"IRB-09-5225","A Multinational, Randomized, Double-blind Study, Comparing the Efficacy of Aflibercept Once Every 2 Weeks versus Placebo in Patients with Metastatic Colorectal Cancer (MCRC) Treated with Irinotecan / 5-FU Combination (FOLFIRI) after failure of an oxaliplatin based regimen(VELOUR) (Protocol: EFC10262)","Darren Sigal","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00561470","Yes"
"IRB-09-5244","A phase III, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multi-center study of ASA404 in combination with docetaxel in second-line treatment of patients with locally advanced or metastatic (Stage IIIb/IV) non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) [Novartis CASA404A2302]
","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00738387","No"
"IRB-09-5361","A Multi-center, Phase 2, Single-Arm, Open-Label Exploratory Study of Individually-Optimized Conditioning Using Pharmacokinetics [PK]-directed Dose Adjustment of Once Daily Intravenous Busulfan, Followed by Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplant in Subjects with Non-Hodgkin’s Lymphoma and Hodgkin’s Lymphoma, Otsuka Protocol No. 273-08-201","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00948090","Yes"
"IRB-10-5417","A Randomized Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study of Everolimus in Combination with Exemestane in the Treatment of Postmenopausal Women with Estrogen Receptor Positive Locally Advanced or Metastatic Breast Cancer who are refractory to Letrozole or Anastrozole [Protocol: CRAD001Y2301]","Rajesh Belani","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00863655","No"
"IRB-10-5430","Randomized, Open-Label, Phase 3 Study of Pemetrexed plus Carboplatin Followed by Maintenance Pemetrexed versus Paclitaxel plus Carboplatin and Bevacizumab Followed by Maintenance Bevacizumab in Patients with Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer of Nonsquamous Histology [H3E-US-S130]","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00948675","Yes"
"IRB-10-5525","A Randomized, Open-Label Phase IIb Trial of Maintenance Therapy with a MUC1 Dendritic Cell Vaccine (CVacTM) for Epithelial Ovarian Cancer Patients in First or Second Remission [Protocol:CAN-003]","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01068509","Yes"
"IRB-10-5543","A Randomized Cross-over Phase 2 Study of the Safety and Efficacy of Two Dose Levels of TH-302 in Combination with Gemcitabine Compared with Gemcitabine Alone in Previously Untreated Patients with Locally Advanced Unresectable or Metastatic Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma [Protocol:TH-CR-404]","Darren Sigal","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01144455","Yes"
"IRB-10-5559","A Phase III randomized, double blind, placebo controlled multi-center study of panobinostat for maintenance of response in patients with Hodgkin’s lymphoma who are at risk for relapse after high dose chemotherapy and autologous stem cell transplant (CLBH589E2301)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01034163","Yes"
"IRB-10-5567","Randomized Phase 3 Trial of Gemcitabine/Carboplatin With or Without BSI-201(SAR240550) (a PARP1 Inhibitor) in Patients with Previously Untreated Stage IV Squamous Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)[Protocol:20090321(EFC11553)] ","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01082549","Yes"
"IRB-10-5627","A randomized, 3 arm, multicentre, phase III study to evaluate the efficacy and the safety of T-DM1 combined with pertuzumab or T-DM1 combined with pertuzumab-placebo (blinded for pertuzumab), versus the combination of trastuzumab plus taxane, as first line treatment in HER2- positive progressive or recurrent locally advanced or metastatic breast cancer Roche BO22589/TDM4788g ROW","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01120184","Yes"
"IRB-10-5632"," A Randomized Phase III Study of Elacytarabine vs. Investigator’s Choice in Patients with Late Stage Acute Myeloid Leukemia [Protocol: CP4055-306]","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01147939","Yes"
"IRB-11-5682","The PARTNER II TRIAL “Placement of AoRTic TraNscathetER” Valves Trial” (US) [Edwards Study 2010-12]","Paul Teirstein","Cardiology and Vascular Diseases","NCT#01314313","Yes"
"IRB-11-5700","A Phase III international, randomized, double-blind, double-dummy study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of 300 mg or 600 mg of intravenous zanamivir twice daily compared to 75 mg of oral oseltamivir twice daily in the treatment of hospitalized adults and adolescents with influenza (Protocol NAI114373)","Farhad Shadan","Pulmonology","NCT01231620","Yes"
"LAJ-06-4342","Virtual HDR Cyberknife Radiosurgery for Localized Prostatic Carcinoma: A Phase II Study","Donald Fuller","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01045148","Yes"
"LAJ-08-8001","Scripps Polster Breast Care Center InvestigatioNal GenebanK (PINK)
","Eric Topol","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00945464","No"
"MER-07-4836","A prospective evaluation of Cyberknife Stereotactic Radiosurgery for low and intermediate risk prostate cancer: emulating HDR brachytherapy dosimetry","Donald Fuller","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00643617","Yes"
"SCC-01-499","Nonmyeloablative Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation for Patients using Antithymocyte Globulin and with Cladribine-Melphalan or Total Lymphoid Irradiation","Jeffrey Andrey","Oncology and Hematology","NCT01272817","Yes"
"SCC-03-2138","NSABP B-35: A Clinical Trial Comparing Anastrozole with Tamoxifen in Postmenopausal Patients with Ductal Carcinoma in Situ (DCIS) Undergoing Lumpectomy with Radiation Therapy","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00053898","No"
"SCC-03-2179","An Open-Label Randomized Phase III Study of Intermittent Oral Capecitabine in Combination with Intravenous Oxaliplatin (Q3W) (XELOX) versus Fluorouracil/Leucovorin as Adjuvant Therapy for Patients who have Undergone Surgery for Colon Carcinoma, AJCC/UICC Stage III (Dukes Stage C) [NO16968D]","Darren Sigal","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00069121","No"
"SCC-04-2503","A Clinical Trial of Adjuvant Therapy Comparing Six Cycles of 5-Flurouracil, Epirubicin and Cyclophosphamide (FEC) to Four Cycles of Adriamycin and Cyclophosphamide (AC), in Patients with Node-Negative Breast Cancer [NSABP B-36]","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00087178","No"
"SCC-04-2589","A Phase III Clinical Trial Comparing Infusional 5-Fluorouracil (5-FU), Leucovorin, and Oxaliplatin (mFOLFOX6) every two weeks with Bevacizumab to the same Regimen without Bevacizumab for the Treatment of Patients with Resected Stages II and III Carcinoma of the Colon (NSABP C-08)","Darren Sigal","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00096278","No"
"SCC-05-2626","NSABP Protocol B-38: A Phase III, Adjuvant Trial Comparing Three Chemotherapy Regimens in Women with Node-Positive Breast Cancer: Docetaxel/Doxorubicin/Cyclophosphamide (TAC); Dose-Dense (DD) Doxorubicin/Cyclophosphamide Followed by DD Paclitaxel (DD AC-->P); DD AC Followed by DD Paclitaxel Plus Gemcitabine (DD AC-->PG)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00093795","No"
"SCC-05-2727","A Randomized Phase III Study of Conventional Whole Breast Irradiation (WBI) versus Partial Breast Irradiation (PBI) for Women with Stage 0, I, or II Breast Cancer [NSABP B-39]","Ray Lin","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00103181","No"
"SCC-05-2762","A Phase III Trial Evaluating the Role of Ovarian Function Suppression and the Role of Exemestane Adjuvant Therapies for Premenopausal Women with Endocrine Responsive Breast Cancer (IBCSG 24-02)","Joan Kroener","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00066690","No"
"SCC-06-4333","A Phase III Randomized, Controlled Trial of Myocet, Trastuzumab and Paclitaxel versus Trastuzumab and Paclitaxel for First Line Therapy of Metastatic Breast Cancer (#STM01-102)","Joan Kroener","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00294996","No"
"SCC-06-4334","A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Phase IIIb Trial Comparing Bevacizumab Therapy with or without Erlotinib after Completion of Chemotherapy with Bevacizumab for the First-Line Treatment of Locally Advanced, Recurrent, or Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer [AVF3671g]","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00257608","No"
"SCC-06-4391","A Clinical Trial Comparing Preoperative Radiation Therapy and Capecitabine with or without Oxaliplatin with Preoperative Radiation Therapy and Continuous Intravenous Infusion of 5-Fluorouracil with or without Oxaliplatin in the Treatment of Patients with Operable Carcinoma of the Rectum (NSABP R-04)","Darren Sigal","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00058474","No"
"SCC-06-4487","A Phase II Trial of 5-Fluorouracil, Leucovorin, and Oxaliplatin (mFOLFOX6) Chemotherapy plus Bevacizumab for Patients with Unresectable Stage IV Colon Cancer and a Synchronous Asymptomatic Primary Tumor (NSABP C-10)","Darren Sigal","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00321828","No"
"SCC-06-4531","Program for the Assessment of Clinical Cancer Tests (PACCT-1): Trial Assigning IndividuaLized Options for Treatment: The TAILORx Trial
(ECOG PACCT-1 TAILORx)","Joan Kroener","Hematology and Oncology","NCT00310180","No"
"SCC-06-4553","A Clinical Trial to Determine the Efficacy of Five Years of Letrozole Compared to Placebo in Patients Completing Five Years of Hormonal Therapy Consisting of an Aromatase Inhibitor (AI) or Tamoxifen Followed by an AI in Prolonging Disease-Free Survival in Postmenopausal Women with Hormone Receptor Positive Breast Cancer (NSABP B-42)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00382070","No"
"SCC-06-4598","A Randomized Phase III Trial of Neoadjuvant Therapy in Patients with Palpable and Operable Breast Cancer Evaluating the Effect on Pathologic Complete Response (pCR) of Adding Capecitabine or Gemcitabine to Docetaxel when Administered before AC with or without Bevacizumab and Correlative Science Studies Attempting to Identify Predictors of High Likelihood for pCR with each of the Regimens [NSABP B-40]","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00408408","No"
"SCC-07-4665","A Randomized, Double-Blind, Multicenter, Placebo-Controlled Study of Adjuvant Lapatinib in Women with Early-Stage ErbB2 Overexpressing Breast Cancer (EGF105485)","Joan Kroener","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00374322","No"
"SCC-07-4681","An Observational Study of AVASTIN®  (Bevacizumab) in Combination with Chemotherapy for Treatment of Metastatic or Locally Advanced and Unresectable Colorectal Cancer and Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung (Excluding Predominant Squamous Cell Histology) [# AVF3991n]","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00388206","No"
"SCC-07-4761","A Phase III Adjuvant Trial of Sequenced EC + Filgrastim + Epoetin Alfa Followed by Paclitaxel Versus Sequenced AC Followed by Paclitaxel Versus CEF as Therapy for Premenopausal Women and Early Postmenopausal Women Who Have Had Potentially Curative Surgery for Node Positive or High Risk Node Negative Breast Cancer (NCIC MA.21)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00014222","No"
"SCC-07-4799","A Phase II Study of the Monoclonal Antibody CT-011 in Patients with Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma following Autologous Peripheral Blood Stem Cell Transplantation (Protocol # CT-2007-01)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00532259","No"
"SCC-07-4803","NSABP PROTOCOL B-41:  A Randomized Phase III Trial of Neoadjuvant Therapy for Patients with Palpable and Operable HER2-Positive Breast Cancer Comparing the Combination of Trastuzumab Plus Lapatinib to Trastuzumab and to Lapatinib Administered with Weekly Paclitaxel Following AC Accompanied by Correlative Science Studies to Identify Predictors of Pathologic Complete Response","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00486668","Yes"
"SCC-07-4867","A Double-Blind, Randomized, Placebo-controlled Phase III Study to Assess the Efficacy of recMAGE-A3 + AS15 Antigen-Specific Cancer Immunotherapeutic as Adjuvant Therapy in Patients with Resectable MAGE-A3-positive Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer [Protocol #109493]","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00480025","Yes"
"SCC-08-4949","A Phase 2, Randomized, Double-Blind, Multicenter Study of Exemestane with and Without SNDX-275 in Postmenopausal Women with Locally Recurrent or Metastatic Estrogen Receptor-Positive Breast Cancer, Progressing on Treatment with a Non-Steroidal Aromatase Inhibitor [SNDX-275-0301]","Joan Kroener","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00676663","No"
"SCC-08-4956","A Phase 2 Open-Label, Multicenter Clinical Study of the Safety and Efficacy of SNS-595 Injection in Patients at Least 60 Years of Age with Previously Untreated Acute Myeloid Leukemia [SPO-0014]","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00607997","No"
"SCC-08-5012","A Multicenter Phase III Randomized Trial of Adjuvant Therapy for Patients with HER2-Positive Node-Positive or High Risk Node-Negative Breast Cancer Comparing Chemotherapy Plus Trastuzumab with Chemotherapy Plus Trastuzumab Plus Bevacizumab (CIRG(TRIO)011/NSABP B-44-I / B020906)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00625898","No"
"SCC-08-7005","An Observational Study of Treatment Patterns and Safety Outcomes for Metastatic or Locally Recurrent Breast Cancer","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00726661","No"
"SCC-08-7007","A multicenter, randomized, double-blind, phase 3 study of sunitinib plus prednisone versus prednisone in patients with progressive metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer after failure of a docetaxel-based chemotherapy regimen [Pfizer: A6181120]","Michael Kosty","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00676650","No"
"SCC-09-7010","An Open-label, Single-arm, Phase 2 Study of Carfilzomib
in Patients with Relapsed and Refractory Multiple
Myeloma (PX-171-003)","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00511238","No"
"SCC-99-4159","Study of Tamoxifen and Raloxifene for the Prevention of Breast Cancer  (STAR)  Protocol NSABP P-2","James Mason","Oncology and Hematology","NCT00003906","No"
