"irb_number","investigator","title","research_type","summary","inclusion_criteria","exclusion_criteria","additional_info","contact_name","contact_email","contact_phone","date_submitted","date_approved"
"HSC-04-2524","Andrew A. White,  M.D.","Aspirin Desensitization in aspirin-exacerbated respiratory disease","Allergy, Asthma, Immunology","This study evaluates new methods of desensitizing patients to aspirin.  It requires 2-3 full days in an outpatient clinic.","* Have chronic sinus disease and/or asthma.  <br>* Have had past reaction to aspirin, ibuprofen or other similar NSAID medication which led to asthma symptoms or sinus symptoms","* Have severe asthma<br>* Use coumadin","Aspirin desensitization is an important treatment for individuals with aspirin-exacerbated respiratory disease (AERD).  ","Andrew White, MD","white.andrew@scrippshealth.org","858-764-9010","2009-09-04 00:00:00","2009-09-07 17:09:46.167000000"
"HSC-07-4789","Eric J Topol,  MD","Study of the Genetics of Healthy Aging","Genetics|Genomics|Healthy Donors","This study will work towards identifying the genetic factors responsible for maintaining health. The study is looking at the DNA of individuals who have lived over 80 years and have not experienced a chronic illness or disease. Participantion requires one visit and includes a small blood sample. ","* Be at least 80 years of age","* Have a history of stroke, cancer or other serious condition","","Sarah Topol","topol.sarah@scrippshealth.org","858-554-5747","2009-06-08 00:00:00","2009-06-08 17:36:49.187000000"
"HSC-07-4835","James Mason,  M.D.","Study to detect genes responsible for the development of solid tumors of the prostate and colon.","Cancer|Colon and Rectal Conditions|Gastroenterology|Genetics|Genomics","This research is to learn more about DNA differences that are linked to the formation of solid tumors.  Requires one 30 minute visit with a study nurse who will review health questions and draw a blood sample.  A tissue sample of the tumor will also be collected at the time of your surgery.","* Be 18 years of age or older, with a solid tumor of the colon or prostate removed at Scripps Green or Scripps Memorial La Jolla Hospital","No Exclusion Criteria","","Sharon Haaser","haaser.sharon@scrippshealth.org","858-554-5758","2009-06-17 00:00:00","2009-08-10 14:34:40.230000000"
"HSC-08-5035","Barbara J Mason,  Ph.D.","New investigational drugs for alcohol dependence","Substance Abuse and Addictions","A 12-week study will be conducted with 150 outpatients with alcohol dependence, with random assignment to pregabalin 300 mg/day, duloxetine 40 mg/day, or placebo in conjuction with behavioral counseling and follow-up visits 1 week and 3 months post-treatment.  Requires 2 screening visits.  Weekly study visits (12) take approximately 1 hour to complete.","* Be 18-65 years of age<br>* Abstain form alcohol at least 4 days, and up to 30 days<br>* Be willing to attend 12 weekly study visits and 2 follow-up visits, with no plans to move out of the greater San Diego area during this period","* Have medical disorders that could increase potential risk or interfere with study participation.<br>* Be sexually active females with childbearing potential who are pregnant, nursing or refuse to use reliable method of birth control.<br>* Be males who refuse to use a reliable form of birth control<br>* Be taking drugs that may increase potential risk or that may affect study outcomes.<br>* Be sent for treatment of alcoholism by a legal authority.","The investigators are testing whether duloxetine and pregabalin might help people with an alcohol problem by normalizing their brain activity after they withdraw from alcohol and improving their mood and sleep.","Susan Quello, B.A., B.S. The Scripps Research Institute","squello@scripps.edu","858-784-7327","2009-06-30 00:00:00","2009-07-02 13:30:37.057000000"
"HSC-08-5067","John Kelso,  MD","Study of rashes that develop in some patients after coronary artery stent placement","Allergy, Asthma, Immunology|Pharmacology|Skin Disorders","Some patients develop rashes after coronary artery stent placement. We are trying to determine the cause and best treatment for these reactions. We will perform skin tests and patch tests that require 2 visits 2 days apart. We will study both patients who have and have not developed a skin rash after this procedure. ","* Have had a coronary artery stent placed <br>* Be taking Plavix ","*  Have already been treated with oral corticosteroids for rash","","Dr. Farrahi","farrahi.farinaz@scrippshealth.org","","2009-09-04 00:00:00","2009-09-07 17:01:24.607000000"
"IRB-09-5177","Charles Fessenden Edwards,  MD","RhD Genotyping test","Gynecology and Obstetrics|Women's Health","This research is being done to see if a new test using fetal DNA found in maternal blood can accurately determine the RhD blood type of the baby.<br><br>","* Be a pregnant female, between 10-16 weeks gestation<br>* Be 18-64 years of age<br>* Be RhD negative","* Be RhD negative with a reaction to a previous Rh positive fetus","Study requires blood sample (2 Tablespoons)","Nancy Giovanetty","giovanetty.nancy@scrippshealth.org","858-764-3023","2009-09-03 00:00:00","2009-09-03 18:45:40.230000000"
"IRB-09-5229","Barbara J Mason,  Ph.D.","Smoking too much pot? We want to help you stop!","Substance Abuse and Addictions","Researchers at The Scripps Research Institute are working to develop treatments to help you quit smoking marijuana. This 12-week treatment program involves the medication gabapentin or placebo in conjunction with weekly behavioral counseling and 1 follow-up visit. Requires 2 screening visits. Weekly study visits (12) take approximately 1 hour to complete, however, two of the visits will be a little bit longer.","* Be 18 to 65 years of age<br>* Be seeking treatment for marijuana use<br>* Be willing to attend 12 weekly study visits and 1 follow-up visit, with no plans to move out of the greater San Diego area during this period","* Have medical disorders that could increase potential risk or interfere with study participation.<br>* Be sexually active females with childbearing potential who are pregnant, nursing or refuse to use reliable method of birth control.<br>* Be males who refuse to use a reliable form of birth control<br>* Be taking drugs that may increase potential risk or that may affect study outcomes.<br>* Be sent for treatment of marijuana use by a legal authority.","The investigators are testing whether gabapentin might help people with a marijuana problem by reducing the severity of withdrawal symptoms like irritability, anxiety, trouble sleeping, and decreased appetite, and therefore decreasing risk and severity of relapse to marijuana use. ","Rebecca Crean, Ph.D. The Scripps Research Institute","rcrean@scripps.edu","","2011-05-04 00:00:00","2011-05-06 08:30:09.713000000"
"IRB-09-5279","Robert K. Eastlack,  MD","OsseoFix Spinal Fracture System to treat Spinal Compression Fractures","Orthopaedic Surgery","This is a new device to repair the vertebra from spinal compression fractures. Patients will be followed up for one year post-op requiring 4 visits.","* Be 55-80 years of age<br>* Have acute painful fracture between T6 and L5","* Have a healed fracture at the intended treatment site<br>* Have a compression fracture at 3 or more levels<br>* Have had spinal surgery within the last year","This procedure is different than a vertebroplasty or kyphoplasty.","Suzanne Daneshvari R.N.","daneshvari.suzanne@scrippshealth.org","858-332-0133","2009-09-10 00:00:00","2009-09-21 14:21:28.633000000"
"IRB-10-5430","Michael P. Kosty,  M.D.","Phase III Study for Lung Cancer","Cancer|Lung Disorders","A study comparing investigational drug to usual treatment for advanced non-small cell lung cancer.  Includes a Treatment Phase (4 cycles of 21 days) followed by a Maintenance Phase (4 or more cycles of 21 days) until disease worsens or side effects become unacceptable. ","*Be diagnosed with advanced non-small cell lung cancer (Stage IV).<br>*Be at least 18 years of age.<br>*Have no prior treatment, with the exception of radiation therapy.<br>*Must be healthy enough to tolerate some walking and light housework and/or office work.","*Be pregnant or nursing.<br>*Have had major surgery or traumatic injury within 28 days of starting treatment.<br>*Have poorly controlled high blood pressure.<br>*Have a history of serious heart disease,stroke or transient ischemic attack (TIA) within 6 months prior to starting treatment.","Subjects are assigned by chance to either the investigational treatment regimen or the usual(Standard of Care)treatment regimen. ","Andrea Van Ducen","VanDucen.Andrea@scrippshealth.org","858-605-7360","2010-05-11 00:00:00","2010-05-11 14:16:49.443000000"
"IRB-10-5498","Paul J. Pockros,  M.D.","New investigational drug for Hepatitis C","Gastroenterology|Hepatology|Liver Diseases","This study will compare Standard of Care (pegylated interferon plus ribavirin) to Standard of Care plus a new investigational drug","Participants must:<br>*Have documented evidence of hepatitis C<br>*Have had no previous treatment for hepatitis C<br>*Have Genotype 1 virus<br>*Be willing to use study approved birth control methods","Participants must not:<br>*Currently be abusing drugs or alcohol<br>*Be infected with HIV<br>*Have been diagnosed with decompensated cirrhosis<br>*Have a history of serious depression or psychiatric<br> illness<br>*Be pregnant, planning to get pregnant or nursing a baby<br>","","Kaye Waite, R.N.","waite.kaye@scrippshealth.org","858-652-5438","2010-07-07 00:00:00","2010-07-08 08:14:06.940000000"
"IRB-10-5515","Paul J. Pockros,  M.D.","Investigational drug for the treatment of NASH (Non Alcoholic Steatohepatitis)","Digestive and Bowel Disorders|Gastroenterology|Hepatology|Liver Diseases","This study will compare two doses of an investigational drug for the treatment of NASH (Non Alcoholic Steatohepatitis)","* Be over 18 years of age<br>* Have a diagnosis of cirrhosis of the liver<br>* Have a liver biopsy if you have not had one within the last 6 months<br>* Use birth-control","* Be abusing drugs or alcohol<br>* Have had previous intestinal or stomach surgery<br>* Have certain other serious medical conditions including other chronic liver disease, unstable diabetes, heart disease, kidney disease","Subjects must be willing to discontinue using certain medications and supplements while participating in this study.","Shari Gilbert, R.N.","gilbert.shari@scrippshealth.org","858-652-5421","2010-08-10 00:00:00","2010-08-10 16:25:19.717000000"
"IRB-10-5543","Darren Sigal,  M.D.","Previously Untreated Advanced Pancreatic Cancer","Cancer","This study compares treatment with standard of care (Gemcitabine) to treatment with an investigational drug (TH-302 + Gemcitabine) for pancreatic cancer. Subjects are assigned by chance to a treatment group. Participation may last up to 29 weeks and include an additional 2 year follow-up period. ","* Be at least 18 years old;<br>* Have previously untreated advanced pancreatic cancer;<br>* Be healthy enough to walk and complete daily light house work or office work;","* Be pregnant or nursing;<br>* Have known disease which has spread to your brain;<br>* Have severe breathing problems;<br>* Have major surgery within 4 weeks of starting study;<br>* Have significant heart disease or heart attack within 6 months of starting study.","","Andrea Van Ducen","VanDucen.Andrea@scrippshealth.org","858-605-7360","2010-09-03 00:00:00","2010-09-10 14:07:03.780000000"
"IRB-10-5552","Christopher Uchiyama,  MD","Study comparing an implantable device to back surgery for leg and low back pain","Neurosurgery|Pain Management","This study compares an implantable device to repeat back surgery for patients who continue to have leg and low back pain after one or more previous back surgeries.  Requires 8 to 11 visits over 3 years.   ","*Have had one or more back surgeries.<br>*Have leg pain with or without low back pain for at least 6 months.<br>*Be 18 years of age or older","*Have more low back pain than leg pain.<br>*Be pregnant or planning a pregnancy.<br>*Have chronic pain in an area other than legs and low back.","","Gail Moore, RN","moore.gail@scrippshealth.org","858-652-5442","2010-09-24 00:00:00","2010-09-27 10:47:38.237000000"
"IRB-10-5572","Steven Poceta,  M.D.","New investigational drug for Post-Herpatic Neuralgia","Neurology","Has your shingles rash healed, yet you are still suffering from symptoms including burning, stabbing pain, sharpness, or sensitivity?  If so, you may have a condition called Post-Herpatic Neuralgia, also known as PHN. We are conducting a clinical research study for people who have experienced these symptoms for at least 9 months after the onset of their shingles rash.  The study will evaluate the effectiveness of an investigational medicine for relieving this specific type of pain. ","-Be between the ages of 18 and 80<br>-Have been diagnosed with Shingles<br>-Be experiencing painful symptoms for at least 9 months after the onset of your shingles rash<br>","-Have a Shingles rash currently present<br>-Have the area of PHN on your face or scalp<br><br>","Qualified participants will receive:<br>-Study related medical care<br>-Study medication<br>-Compensation for time and travel","Crystal Sanchez","sanchez.crystal@scrippshealth.org","(858) 652-5440","2011-01-31 00:00:00","2011-02-01 13:14:10.180000000"
"IRB-10-5635","Charles R Smith,  MD","New investigational drug treatment for multiple sclerosis","Multiple Sclerosis|Neurology","This study will compare an investigational drug to treat multiple sclerosis with a currently available treatment.  Requires clinic visits every 4 weeks for about 3 years. All study medication and study related medical care will be provided at no cost.   ","Have relapsing remitting multiple sclerosis.<br>Have had a relapse within the last 3 years.<br>Be 18 to 55 years of age.<br>Be willing to use study approved birth control methods.","Be pregnant, nursing or planning pregnancy in the next 3 1/2 years.<br>Have a history of cancer.<br>Have a history of infection with HIV virus, hepatitis B virus or hepatitis C virus.<br>Have a history of seizure disorder.<br>","Additional restrictions may apply.","Gail Moore, R.N.","moore.gail@scrippshealth.org","858-652-5442","2011-01-26 00:00:00","2011-02-10 12:20:25.587000000"
"IRB-11-5705","E. Victor Ross,  M.D.","Pixel RF Treatment- Facial Acne Scars and Abdominal Stretch Marks","Dermatology|Laser and Cosmetic Dermatology","This study will evaluate the safety and efficacy of Pixel RF(fractional radio frequency)treatment of acne scars and stretch marks. Requires about 7 visits over about 5 months.","*Be male or female 21-75 years of age.<br>*Have acne scars on the face, or<br>*Have stretch marks on the abdomen.<br>*Be able to follow study visit schedule.<br>","*Have an impaired immune system, or active infections. <br>*Have taken any Isotretinoin, i.e. Accutane, within 6 mos. <br>*Have connective tissue disease. <br>*Have burns or poor-healing in the treatment area. <br>*Have metal implants near the treatment area. <br>*Have an implantable pacemaker or automatic<br> defibrillator/cardioverter(AICD).<br>*Have had ablative/non-ablative cosmetic procedure within<br> 3 months in the treatment area.<br>*Have active cancer, collagen or vascular disease.<br>*Be pregnant or think might become pregnant.<br>*Have used certain medications within 30 days of treatment.<br>","","Nancy Houghton","houghton.nancy@scrippshealth.org","","2011-05-26 00:00:00","2011-05-26 18:21:21.460000000"
"LAJ-06-4342","Donald Fuller,  M.D.","Virtual HDR CyberKnife Radiosurgery for Localized Prostatic Carcinoma","Cancer|Radiation Oncology","This study will evaluate the effects of CyberKnife prostate radiosurgery in terms of morbidity/quality of life, relative to other commonly used methods of prostate cancer treatment and the pattern of PSA decline and biochemical relapse-free survival thereafter.","*Have a histologically  confirmed adenocarcioma of the prostate, clinical stage T1b-T2b, NX/N0, M0<br>*Have a Karnofsky performance status greater than 80<br>* Be 18+ years of age<br>*Be judged to have localized prostate cancer as determined by the following circumstances: Gleason sum equal to or less than 7, prostate-specific antigen equal to or less than 10 ng/ml, prostate volumes by TRUS less than or equal to 80 cc.","*Have stage less than T1b, T2c, T3 or T4 disease<br>*Gleason score greater than 7<br>*PSA greater than 10 ng/ml<br>*Lymph node involvement (N1)<br>*Evidence of distant metastases (M1)<br>*Radical surgery for carcinoma of the prostate, prior pelvic radiation, pelvic surgeical clips or other metallic foreign bodies<br>*History of hormonal therapy (antiandrogen or 5 alpha reductase treatment within three months prior to treatment)<br>*Previous or concurrent cancers other than basal, in situ, or squamous cell skin cancers unless disease-free for equal to or greater to 5 years<br>*Major medical or psychiatric illness<br>*Metallic Hip prothesis<br>*History of inflammatory bowel disease","","Carlyn Tripp","ctripp@rmgmed.com","","2010-09-08 00:00:00","2010-09-09 13:37:43.920000000"
"MER-07-4836","Donald Fuller,  M.D.","CyberKnife Stereotactic Radiosurgery for Prostate Cancer","Cancer|Radiation Oncology","This study will compare CyberKnife radiosurgery versus HDR brachytherapy for selected prostate cancer patients to affirm comparable radiation safety and cancer control efficacy between these two techniques.  Requires MRI for treatment planning, 4-5 daily treatments, and follow up appointments with PSA/Testosterone testing, and questionnaire completion.","*Must be 18+ years of age<br>*Must have a histologically proven prostate adenocarcinoma<br>*Have Gleason score of 2-7 (to be reviewed by reference lab)<br>*Have had a prostate biopsy within one year of the date of registration<br>*Have a PSA less than or equal to 20<br>*Have a clinical stage T1b-T2b, N0-Nx, M0-Mx (AJCC 6th Edition)","*Have had no prior prostatectomy or cryotherapy of the prostate<br>*Have had no prior radiotherapy to the prostate or lower pelvis<br>*Have no implanted hardware or other material that would prohibit appropriate treatment planning or delivery<br>*Have had no chemotherapy for a malignancy in the last 5 years<br>*Have had no history of an invasive malignancy (other than this prostate cancer, or basal or squamous skin cancers) in the last 5 years.<br>","","Carlyn Tripp","ctripp@rmgmed.com","","2010-09-08 00:00:00","2010-09-09 13:35:04.880000000"
"SCC-07-4803","James Mason,  M.D.","NSABP Protocol B-41-I  ","Cancer","This study will compare a new targeted treatment (Lapatinib)with a standard treatment (trastuzumab)for HER2-positive breast cancer. The combination of Trastuzumab plus Lapatinib will be compared to Trastuzumab alone, and Lapatinib administered with weekly Paclitaxel, all following standard chemotherapy. ","* Be female.<br>* 18 years of age or older.<br>* Able to swallow oral medications. ","* Have had an excisional biopsy or lumpectomy prior to study entry.<br>* Have clinical or radiologic evidence of metastatic disease.<br>* Have synchronous bilateral invasive breast cancer.<br>* Have had any prior treatments for this cancer; including radiation therapy, chemotherapy, and/or targeted therapy.<br>* Have prior therapy with anthracyclines, taxanes, trastuzumab, or lapatinib for any malignancy.<br>* Have any cardiac disease that would preclude the use of the drugs included in the B-41 treatment regimens.<br>* Have uncontrolled hypertension, defined as blood pressure > 150/90 mm/Hg on antihypertensive therapy. (Patients with hypertension that is well-controlled on<br>medication are eligible.)<br>* Be pregnant or nursing.  <br>","Please contact us for more information, including a complete list of inclusion and exclusion criteria.  <br> <br>","Andrea Van Ducen","VanDucen.Andrea@scrippshealth.org","858-605-7360","2010-06-01 00:00:00","2010-06-01 13:33:27.400000000"
